[Music]
foreign
observational study on acne reported a
statistically significant relationship
between acne severity and dietary
factors such as chocolate and dairy
products both of which I have videos
about
this surprised me sunflower seed
consumption when I think sunflower seeds
I just think good whole food source of
nutrition found to lower cholesterol
levels as much as almonds which is
pretty good there are however right and
wrong ways to eat them if you sit down
and eat a pound of unshelled sunflower
seeds just eat them with the shell still
on you can end up corked with a
fist-sized mass of shredded sunflower
seed shells How could a doctor diagnose
such a thing by the colonic crunch sign
of course sounds like a breakfast cereal
served in hell but rather it's when you
palpate a large crunchy rectal Mass I've
got a picture for you of course
can end up a sharp thorny Mass which is
why the so-called sunflower seed
Syndrome has been described as a prickly
proctological problem lamenting that
people who consume Health Foods
occasionally fall into the Trap of
believing if some is good more is better
it's not the amount though
it's how they're eating them with the
shells still on that's why the syndrome
is uncommon unless the patients are
children who don't know any better or
adults who are either impaired or have
no experience with eating sunflower
seeds
most cases involve younger children but
here researchers describe a
psychologically sound 13 year old
stressing the importance of the role of
the parents to guide their children
about potential problems associated with
the ingestion of too many unshelled
seeds
you can overdo even shelled seeds though
because of just the nature of sunflowers
they're good at drying up the naturally
occurring heavy metal cadmium out of the
ground so end up with higher levels than
most Foods even if grown in relatively
uncontaminated soil the people who
consume large amounts of sunflower seeds
don't seem to suffer any untoward
effects or even end up with detectively
higher cadmium levels and here they
defined large amounts as greater than an
ounce a week which is like a handful
about 150 seeds
the World Health Organization recommends
staying below about 490 micrograms of
dietary cadmium a week meaning if you
ate a handful a day you'd be well below
that but you may get as much as 36 a day
from the rest of your diet so I think
one handful a day is a reasonable safe
upper limit
yeah but will it give us acne you don't
know until you put it to the test
yeah but who's going to do a randomized
controlled trial of sunflower seeds and
acne nobody
until now after all consuming sunflower
seeds is a very enjoyable way of
participating in a clinical trial
50 young adults were randomized to eat
sunflower seeds or not for a week in the
control group the acne severity index
stayed about the same but in the
sunflowers seed group they got worse
this translates into about three extra
pimples in the sunflower group versus
about one extra in the control group
they conclude that sunflower seed intake
appears to aggravate acne however
further Evidence may be needed before
Banning sunflower seed intake in
patients with acne
[Music]
thank you